♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ somewhere in time
and space ♪
♪ mike nelson
and his robot pals ♪
♪ are caught in
an endless chase ♪
♪ pursued by a woman
whose name is pearl ♪
♪ an evil gal who wants
to rule the world ♪
♪ she threw a few things
in her purse ♪
♪ and in her rocket ship
she hunts him ♪
♪ all across the universe ♪
[Pearl]
I'll get you!
♪ I'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst I can find--
la la la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ and I'll monitor his mind--
la la la ♪
♪ now, keep in mind,
mike can't control ♪
♪ where the movies begin
or end-- la la la ♪
♪ he'll try to keep
his sanity ♪
♪ with the help
of his robot friends ♪
♪ robot roll call ♪
You're on!
Oh, my stars!
Check me out!
I'm different!
♪ If you're wondering how ♪
♪ he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts--
la la la ♪
♪ just repeat to yourself,
"it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really
just relax" ♪
♪ for mystery
science theater ♪
♪ 3000 ♪
Hi, everyone. Welcome
to the satellite of love.
My name is mike nelson.
Or it used to be.
You see, until recently,
I was just like you.
I believed that everything that
was taught me was right,
and everything
was as it seemed.
And then one day,
I found myself pursued
by agents of
a secret government project
who basically wiped out
every shred of evidence
that I ever existed.
They took everything,
my identity, my life.
Now I'm on the run,
never knowing
when I'll be caught,
or where my enemies
will turn up.
But they should know,
I will do anything
to get back what is mine.
- Hey, mike!
- Mike.
- Yeah?
We found your wallet.
It was in your room.
- Oh. [Laughs]
- Yeah.
Everything about your identity
is there, you can relax.
Guess I didn't have to
do very much at all
to get back what's mine.
- No.
- You weren't telling them about
the secret government
conspiracy, were you?
Well, my wallet was missing.
Now, folks, listen,
pay no attention to this guy.
Everything is
exactly as it seems.
Ah, we'll be right back--
wait a minute...
Wait a minute, how do I know
this wallet is mine?
It is. Look, same picture
of mark spitz, even.
- Oh, good.
- Sad, really.
♪♪
Gotta say, it's good
to have the old identity back--
- aah! Aah!
- What? What?
They took--
the took my identity!
Everything I ever-- oh, wait,
it's right here. Sorry.
Phew.
Oh, mrs. Forrester's calling.
And you want to hang on
to an identity like that, huh?
Sheesh.
- Aloha! Welcome aboard.
- Aloha!
Welcome. Bobo,
I think the idea
is to distribute them
one-by-one,
and then let the guests
handle it from there.
Oh, I get it. Silly me.
Hello! Aloha! Welcome!
Bobo, you idiot!
Come, let me show you
to a cabin.
- Ow! Ow!
- Arrivederci!
Son of nel, listen.
Our phone number
accidentally got printed
in an ad
for a cruise ship deal.
Bobo took 2,500 reservations
before he told me.
But the money's so sweet,
I decided to keep it.
Then we left port
before they could get on.
[Chuckling]
Well, except
for those two early nerds.
But...
[Chuckling]
We left 2,498 suckers ashore.
But you live in a castle, so...
[Chuckling]
Shut up. Okay, we gotta give 'em
the whole q.E.-Ii deal,
so we need ice sculptures
for the buffet table.
Hey, hey, clorox face,
send them the raw materials.
Aye aye, sir!
Shut up and just do it.
Right.
[Digital sound]
Boy...
- Huh?
- Huh.
Huh.
Anne and I would like
to see the upper deck now.
Oh, sure, but-- oh, the seas
are too rough right now!
- Oh, yes.
- Whoa, feel that?
Too rough to feed you, even.
But still,
smell that salt air.
I'm getting sick, norm.
Mrs. Dash air, actually.
Hey maw giver, it's not
too rough to feed me, is it?
I mean, it's not too rough--
oh!
Okay, let's see what you got.
Well, now, I made a,
sort of, environmental sculpture
with my ice.
Setting it in a surrounding
of gin and tonic.
Aesthetically pleasing,
and very, very refreshing.
Uh, I uh...
I-- I tried to...
To weld mine.
- And, uh...
- Yeah, you did.
I don't know.
Well, I give you
michelangelo's david.
Wow, crow, bigger
than the original.
- And out of four ice cubes?
- I'm just efficient, I guess.
- Man.
- Yeah, I could have, uh...
Could have done that, I guess,
but i-- I was, uh...
Trying to weld mine, and--
right, mike,
you made that clear.
And now it's time
for your on-deck movie.
To be held below decks today
because of
the aforementioned rough seas.
[Shouting]
It's called devil fish,
and it features
many nautical themes
and many italians
pretending to be floridians.
Mike and bots, also enjoy.
- Brain pan, send it.
- Yeah.
[Digital sound]
He just needs
a little off the calf here.
No, stop it!
Good gravy, man.
Don't you ever learn?
[Buzzer sounds]
Sorry-- oh, we got
movie sign!
No accumulated knowledge
at all.
[Mike]
Sorry.
[Crow]
It's okay.
Hey, bebe rebozo's
home movies.
I told him, you know.
And I told her,
loudly and clearly--
yes, dear.
Yes, dear.
I'm doing it, dear.
Who was it that said,
"I never met a kid I liked?"
W.c. Fields, I think.
Well, that's the way
I feel about 'em
when they're on my boat.
Oh, I mean us.
2,000 flushes, the movie.
Something vague
this way comes.
Carl, are you
listening to me?
Yeah, molly,
I'm listening to you.
Mostly, I'm eating.
You know what she had
the nerve to say?
You know what she said?
What she said, after this.
Ow!
Oh, carl,
did you cut yourself?
Relax, I mean,
it's just a scratch.
And it could get infected.
I'll go get the iodine.
Ooh. It's gertrude stein.
[Growling]
Well, I can eat the boat,
and spit them out, I suppose.
We now return
to the cut finger story.
Man, it's farther up
than I thought.
This is taking forever.
Aah, save the metamucil.
Film crew's really having fun
throwing stuff at her.
- Carl! Carl!
- Caw! Caw!
[Carl screaming]
I guess he didn't like
the pork tartare.
- Carl?
- Mrs. Kilroy was here.
Carly?
Let me clear the table off
for you ma'am. Thanks.
Our special tonight
is devil fish
with satanic string beans
and deep-lucifered potatoes.
- [Screaming]
- This fish has a lot of nerve.
Ooh, yeah, we got dolphins
in the basement.
Uh-oh.
No! Wrong! Do it again.
[Dolphins clicking]
♪ This is the dawning
of the age of seaquarium ♪
Peter frampton!
[Laughing]
Man, the staten island ferry
is way off course.
♪♪ [Humming]
No, don't put me in there!
There's sharks in there!
Oh, wait.
Hey, temp-workers.
I'm pleased at things.
No, no, I'm not
gonna fall for that.
No, really, I am
getting divorced, toots.
Oh, you.
Hey, fish now!
Hey, you haven't thanked me.
Come here, donald.
Come on.
Hey, don't call me donald.
My name is... [dolphin sounds]
Ah.
Shush up.
Now, how would you
rate that fish?
You've had enough.
[Choking]
Ugh, what did you put
in that fish?
You're a fatty!
Now that concludes
our tour inside.
Outside, the outdoor pool,
where the dolphins are together
with researcher stella dickens,
their trainer.
This way.
- Isn't that something?
- They can move.
What do you do exactly?
I study their behavior
here in captivity,
and also
in their natural habitat.
And right now, dr. Bob hogan,
my associate,
is at sea,
conducting an experiment.
Dr. Bob hogan's also
experimenting with film credits.
Devil fish, the story
of aleister crappie.
Hey look, they spelled
his name sideways.
It's a man wearing
a london phone booth.
Hey, a turtle.
So, mike, turtles excrete wax,
and you humans put it in cans
and just rub it
all over your cars?
Good, that's good.
Just keep doing that.
That's not exactly
how it goes.
Say, uh, whose fish is this?
Somebody lose this fish?
Man, feeding
the whole ocean is hard.
♪ Don't say things
you're gonna... ♪
General organizer,
just put some things
over there and over there.
They're going to air-lift us
out of the movie!
- Here we are! Here we are!
- Right here! Here!
- Ah.
- Hey!
[Boom]
- Ah.
- Doesn't see us.
1-4-2-1 here. 1-4-2-1.
We're over the area.
No sign of anything yet.
While there are things,
of course,
I engage in hyperbole
to make a point, however.
Ah, what a great job. I'm glad
I wussed out of vietnam.
Man, what a crummy
boat design.
- Okay, 1-4-2-1 here.
- Yeah.
We spotted him.
We will attempt recoup.
♪ Devil fish in love ♪
♪ devil fish in love ♪
Donald.
Well, how do you do, sir?
Yeah, yeah, banter,
banter, banter, fish!
Nice to know you.
Very good.
There you go.
When dumb guys snorkel.
- Ready, man?
- Right!
Go!
- Aah!
- Oh, great coast guard.
It's gonna be cold!
Please.
Get the harness out.
- Get the hardness out?
- That's what I heard.
Hang on, old chum.
Ha, I kid the dead guy.
- [Laughter]
- Wow.
I'm getting dizzy.
Oh, isn't this an orange juice?
Oh, darn.
The director's vision,
lots of shots of things.
Stand by to harness.
♪ Too much time
on my hands ♪
Uh, is this guy that important?
Why don't they just leave him?
I don't know.
Early parasailing.
Give stella a big hug.
Come on. Up, up, up...
[Applause]
You know,
just because you can edit,
doesn't mean you should.
I tried to unclog my lawnmower
with my feet.
Ooh.
Come on, beer,
get in my mouth. Come on!
[Instruments whirring]
[Imitating noises]
I've located
a gary wright song.
My goodness.
That's my special line.
A beer
is in trouble somewhere.
Ah, transport me, marc cohn.
I feel like I actually am
walking in memphis.
Huh, I didn't know humans
could survive without flesh.
Donald, minnie, what's wrong?
- [Racecar sounds]
- What's wrong?
Donald!
What is it?
I bet they have beautiful
hardwood under that carpeting.
Minnie, stop! Stop it!
What's wrong?
♪♪
I'm out of beer.
It's coming
right at the boat!
Oh, my god.
They hanged bobo!
Come on, legs, evolve!
What are you doing?
What's happened?
- Minnie! Donald!
- Clarence! Paul! Raif! Luigi!
[Screaming]
Well, she's too gristly,
too much bone to eat.
Say, we're about to have
one of our dolphin orgies,
if you're...
[Yelps]
Ah, they pantsed me.
His hair's getting all tangled
in the reel-to-reel.
He's listening to "awaken
the beer drinker within."
I did my own splenectomy
and saved.
Well, doc,
what's the story?
Runaway bunny.
At first sight,
I'd say it was a shark.
And a big one at that.
But not necessarily.
Look.
Whoa! One thing's
not bit off.
The bite is clean
like a shark's,
but the teeth marks
puzzled me.
And so does
the size of the bite.
For me it could have been caused
by something else.
Other than a shark, that is.
I did it.
Well, you could have
the body photographed.
Wouldn't hurt.
- Take care of it, cortez.
- Duh.
- And take some shots
for our records, too.
- Duh, okay.
- Okay, sheriff.
- Let's hope you're wrong.
I usually am, so...
I just don't understand
what happened to those dolphins.
They took my conditioner.
They've never
behaved this way before.
- Quiet a second, stella.
- Hey, they almost
killed me, bob!
Are you listening to me?
I'd say something extraordinary
happened to both of us, then.
I made a recording.
Tell me what you think.
Whatever it was,
it almost made me capsize.
[Gulping]
[Lip smacking, cans opening]
[Drinking sounds continue]
What's the matter?
I'm sure I recorded it.
Recorded what?
That sound.
That strange sound.
I've never heard
anything like it.
- It was almost like a voice.
- A voice?
Did I say voice?
I meant doorknob.
No, not exactly
a voice, it...
Was more of
a terrifying sound.
- Full of hate.
- Hate?
Yeah, yeah, that's it.
- Hate.
- Oh, bob dornan.
When did you hear it?
At about 10:00.
Wait, I'll check my notes.
Yes, here it is. 10:00,
heard voice filled with hate.
I picked it up at 10:18.
And it lasted
for three minutes.
Like my last 12-pack.
That's exactly
the time the dolphins
started going in circles.
Don't you think
there's a connection there?
Why didn't I get it on tape?
Because you were drunk?
Maybe it was too high
or too low a frequency.
Kenneth.
Then you know
what I'm thinking?
That peter is the only one
that can help us.
Yeah, peter allen.
- Peter?
- Allen.
Man, abyss ii
isn't very good.
♪♪
Is that fab or rob?
Ugh, you colored girls
who have considered suicide
when the rainbow is enuf.
[Chuckles]
- You call this working?
- What?
I said,
"do you call this working?"
- I can't hear you.
- I'm listening to shonen knife.
♪♪ [Music stops]
Now you can hear me.
You think?
Well, how about that monitor
that needed fixing?
I checked all the circuits,
and they're all screwed up.
- Impossible to fix.
- Aw.
The only thing that's screwed up
is your head.
- What the--?
- What was that?
The only thing
that's screwed up, funny man,
- is your head.
- Hello?
Mm, that's because
you're a genius.
Look, it took me five years
to make this place go.
Try not to destroy it
in the next ten days.
When are you leaving?
Right now, sandra.
And if there's
anything else you need...
Why don't you
take me with you?
Because your dress
like robin williams.
Because somebody
has to watch the store.
Because there's about
three gorgeous ladies
waiting for me in new york.
The delrubio sisters.
Heads up, sandra.
Ribbit.
Of course I am american
and not italian.
I drive a truck.
♪♪ [Humming]
I think I'll put up the sail.
- Hi, peter.
- Hi, stick.
- Hi, stella.
- I need your help.
Oh, no, I'm going
on vacation.
Only got a couple of seconds
to spare.
A genius
doesn't need any more.
What's this?
I'm thinking of becoming
daryl hannah.
It's a list of the equipment
that bob and I'll need.
You've got to be kidding.
I'd have to go to america--
oh, wait.
I'm going away. This stuff's
all gotta be built to specs.
- Please.
- I'm skinny.
It's very important.
Who else can I turn to?
Ugh, take at least a day.
Yeah, and you can do it
in a few hours.
Hmm?
I'll see you later.
Enjoy the sides
of my breasts.
Sure-- oh.
Who was that, and how
do we know each other?
Tiny medical center,
starring tiny chad everett.
Hey, that's rip torn in drag.
Welcome to the world
of "woi."
Yes, here at woi,
we do this kind of thing.
[Imitating drums
and animals chattering]
Gotta finish this bomb
for pakistan by saturday.
Somebody swiped
the microwave.
I am perfecting the fizzy.
Yes.
[Computerized voice]
I love you, davis.
[Imitating voice]
Hi, honey. I'm here.
Who else
would it have been?
Not larry storch,
I don't think.
But you should be more careful.
Why?
Someone might
intercept the message.
Hmm.
It's not likely, though.
My husband's only interested
in winning a nobel,
and the others are much too busy
to worry about us.
Where have you been?
On the challenger, we took
some samples of plankton.
The sea was marvelous.
I heard they fished another
dead body from the ocean.
Got him in the nets.
Oh, I'll bet they'll
come around bothering us again.
They still don't understand
that we at the w.O.I.
Deal with genetics,
not fish.
That and other things.
Hmm.
Here, let me
activate your culture.
- Oh, doctor.
- Hi, I'm here to enter data.
Dyan cannon's watching us.
That's... what's her name.
[Yawning]
Beautiful. That does it.
- It's very odd.
- We connect it to the pulse
generator to connect the phase.
- [Yawns]
- Weird.
Will you stop yawning?
You're putting me to sleep.
Look, you won't be able
to finish it before tomorrow
morning anyway.
I have to.
I'm not giving up my vacation.
Stella gets to you.
Doesn't she?
Yes, she's
a very attractive radio.
That's exactly right.
Ah, the heavily sexed world
of appliance repair.
Maybe you can read something
in these shots
that I can't see.
No, it's just you nude
at the forest preserve.
What do you think?
You know more
about sharks than I do.
Well, he needs new pants.
Good god.
I've never seen anything
quite like this.
- Me neither.
- You?
Mind if I keep them
and study them a while?
Okay, doctor.
If you come up with anything,
get in touch as soon
as possible.
I want to be
ahead of the game
before I point the finger
at anybody.
Oh, I suppose I'll accept
a little bit of sex from you.
- Go ahead.
- ♪♪ [ambiance funk]
[Imitating adult film music]
Wakka-chukka-boom.
Chukka-wakka-chukka boom.
Slip, bra, teddy, bra, panty,
peignoir, slip, bra.
- [Doorbell tinkles]
- [Gasps]
Well, that's it, mike.
It's close as I'll ever come.
It's my daily victoria secret
delivery.
[Doorbell tinkling]
Does she live
in a department store?
Just a minute.
I'm sexy.
[Gasps]
Hey, hartley.
What are you up to, miller?
- Wakka-chukka...
- What are you doing here?
Wakka-chukka-boom.
Chukka-wakka-chukka boom.
Tell your boss,
I can't afford to fool around.
His time is up.
He don't feel that way.
♪♪ [Humming]
You know, dolphins are really
smart, aren't they?
Oh, yeah, totally.
Smart as you please.
Oh, yeah, the way they
jump for things.
- Yeah.
- And click and buzz
to kind of talk,
flip over and...
Swim.
There's that.
And eat fish.
- Yeah.
- Other things, I guess.
You know, dolphins are really
dumb, aren't they?
Hell, I don't know anymore.
What's with dolphins anyways,
you guys?
Are they smart
or are they dumb?
Well, let's find out.
I have seaworld
on my speed dial.
Let's just call them and see.
[Dialing, ringing]
[Man]
It's a great day at seaworld.
How may I direct your call?
Hi, yeah, blowy the dolphin,
please.
I'll connect you.
Blowy?
Yeah, there's always a blowy.
[Dolphin clicks]
Hi, blowy?
Mike nelson here.
See, we have a rather delicate
question for you.
[Clicking]
So are you guys just stupid
or what's going on anyway?
[Squeaking]
Yeah, I mean,
if you're so smart,
how come you don't speak
english or play the drums?
[Squeaking]
Yeah...
That's your answer
to everything, pal.
- Well, listen up, flipper.
- Blowy.
Yeah, blowy, whatever.
Everyone thinks you're
einstein or something.
We think you're just an
evolutionary cul-de-sac,
couldn't swim your way
out of a hot tub.
What do you think
of them sardines?
[Squeaking]
Oh, yeah.
Hey, tell it to fa, pal.
Or better yet,
why don't you talk to me?
Come on up here.
Let your flippers
do the talking
because I am standing here,
man.
I'm waiting for you.
Come on.
Bring it on.
[Laser pulses]
Alarm. A dolphin war ship
has just de-cloaked
off the port bow.
Cambot, get me
rocket number nine.
Its propulsion
and weapons systems
are advanced far beyond
our understanding.
[Whimpering]
[Dolphin squeaking]
Hi, uh, blowy?
We're sorry about everything.
Yeah, we didn't understand.
So, again, sorry.
Take it all back.
Sorry. Sorry about that.
Bye.
[Sighs]
You know, dolphins
are really smart.
- Sure are.
- Yeah, really smart,
but touchy.
Be right back.
Man, say the slightest thing.
There, it's fixed.
- Hey!
- Stop in the name of europe.
What the hell are you doing?
It's a middleton group
of tube-amp lovers.
Kick, punch,
it's all in the mind.
He's enjoying the bold,
adventurous life
of a tv repairman.
You bastard lou reed.
Let's go.
Stay. I'll put coffee on.
[Sandra]
Peter! Peter!
I'm over here.
♪ Over here, over here ♪
Oh, my god, peter.
Is-a your penis okay?
What happened?
They smashed the converter.
You work all night,
and they come and smash it
to bits.
Do you think you could
identify them?
No. They were only interested
in that damn converter.
Smashed it to bits.
Oh, hey, mr. Food,
the fishing guy.
Whoops.
♪♪ [Soft strings]
Sounds like they're in search
of the mysterious underwater
yanni caves.
He's getting paid 10 large
to whack a grouper.
I just ate harvey mackay.
You know, you shoot scuba
diving in slow motion,
you could actually go
back in time.
A human!
We've got to clear the oceans.
Oh, no, there's that shark
that asked me out.
Shark!
Help! Shark!
Give me a hand!
It's going away.
My rash-- it's going away.
I'm made of ground chalk
and lava.
[Slow motion]
Slow day, hun?
- Let's get out of here.
- Yeah, yeah.
Florinda was
one of my associates,
one of the best.
Uh, associates,
as I mentioned.
Her death will be
a serious loss to us.
Boy, could she type
and light file.
I must say she wasn't feeling
any too well lately.
Do you think it was
an accident,
or could she have
committed suicide?
Huh?
I think that's up to you
to decide.
Yeah, right on.
Well, we did accident yesterday.
That was kind of boring.
I think I'll decide on murder.
What the hell?
You know if she had
any enemies?
No, absolutely not.
When was the last time
you saw her?
Yesterday.
In the morning,
when she left the lab.
And so none of you knew
she was going on a trip.
- She had just packed her bags--
- sheriff.
Here at the w.O.I.
We don't poke into people's
private affairs.
All we know about florinda
is that she was
an excellent researcher.
What specific research
did florinda do?
She was working on the
properties of ribonucleic acid.
That's a substance necessary
to life.
Like cigarettes, fire,
and thumbs.
Come on.
Let's see what you can do.
Well, this is about it.
I hate to disappoint you.
Hey, slow down!
Come back here.
Where you going?
[Gasps]
Fluffy, bad dog.
Open to downtown shackville.
Hey, rob reiner.
Hurry up.
Our shift's almost over.
This guy just fell asleep, sir.
It's hard to believe, sheriff.
- Cortez?
- Yes, sir.
I want a cast
made of that wound.
- Go on.
- Yes, sir.
Good thing yoko's there.
[Groaning]
I can't believe I directed
north.
Can't believe I got sent
to the principal's office again.
Well, doc?
We're saving him,
but he's still in shock.
Any chance of interrogating--
[woman]
Doctor, hurry!
- Hardly.
- What's wrong?
- Another crisis.
- The nurse needs
making out with.
- The sedative.
- Yes.
Here you go.
This'll make your coat shiny.
[Doctor]
That should do it.
Stay with him.
Yes, doctor.
May I come in, please?
We might get some information
form the cast taken
of his friend's arm.
I examined the body carefully,
and I can say without a doubt
they were both attacked
by the same animal,
the same shark.
Another dark-shaded,
mobbed-up doctor.
Whatever it is, I think it's
good we took it out of him.
Good morning, doctor.
My god, what the hell is that?
Whatever it is, I wouldn't want
to rub it the wrong way.
Well, I would.
- I'm not an expert...
- But this is pointy.
...but these don't look like
the teeth marks
of a shark to me.
What else you think
it might be then?
I'll answer that as soon as we
cut back to our scene.
It shouldn't be long.
Try it now.
I get nothing.
Nothing.
No respect.
What do you mean nothing?
Did you put the fuse in?
Of course I inserted
the damn fuse.
What do you take me for?
No comment.
Oh, he threw
a little euro-tantrum.
They've been going on
like that all morning.
Geniuses should never
work together.
But these two guys'll be fine.
Sandra. Sandra.
Yes, master?
Don't be a wise...
And go see what's wrong
with the monitor.
Yeah.
I want to come up here
and pout a little bit.
Is that okay
if I pout a little?
Think it'll work?
What, are you kidding?
I like the color of your eyes.
The rest of you is hideous.
Bye.
Okay, genius, we're getting
a signal here.
Finally. I'm going below.
Stay tuned.
All right.
[Foreign accent]
Boy, am I from florida.
Isn't that one guy's
eye color gross?
When will he be ready?
Just a couple more hours.
I'm going back to italy.
Bye.
Kiss my ink sac.
♪♪ [Hums "sailor's hornpipe"]
Crap.
I'm sorry about your vacation.
Oh, really?
Oh, no, he suspects my
insincerity about his vacation.
So far I like these scenes
the best.
I was going to say how sorry
I was about your cat dying,
but forget it.
[Beeping]
Oh, I forgot to lick
the beer off the can.
[Electronic sound]
What's that?
- Kraftwerk.
- Not sure.
Hang on a second.
- Wait.
- Hold on. Wait. Pause.
Okay, we got it.
A shark?
You think it's him?
I don't know.
Might be.
It's moving fast,
almost 30 knots.
Judging from the sound
of its echo,
displaces a tremendous
amount of water for a fish.
Do you read anything else?
I don't know.
Must've dived too deep.
Yeah, to say the least.
Maybe it wasn't him.
Hey, bob, save us a beer, too.
Huh?
I was framed, I tell ya.
You want another?
Then find that fish.
That's euro-funny.
Now, how do these fit?
You did a good job.
Buy yourself something ugly.
Need anything else?
Just keep an eye on him.
I'll let you know
when we need something else.
Man, jet skis
are getting huge.
I was only 19 when I met bob.
That's when I was skinny.
He was with the english
oceanic institute
before coming to florida.
I liked working
with him immediately.
Cello, 12 fathoms.
Okay, it's him!
Peter!
Oh, incoming.
[Chuckles]
I hung one out for fun.
I think it's that thing
that comes out of
the wizard of id's cauldron.
[Rumbling]
It's his sound.
It's him.
What do I think?
Come on, baby.
Come on up.
♪ Slow ride ♪
We've got three hours
before it gets here.
Wanna play risk?
Let's see if he records.
[Gurgling]
♪ I dream of jeanie ♪
You bloody, rotten, filthy sod,
let me hear you.
Well, glub, I guess.
It's bearing 1.2.0.
Coming up at us two points
off the starboard bow.
[Woman]
How big is it?
I don't know.
Do you think it will record?
Let's hope so.
Although we are having
tentacle difficulties.
This should filter out
all the interference
once I lock on to
his frequency.
It'll be computerized.
- Then we'll be able to--
- [howling]
God.
What's the matter?
Hard to tell.
I think it's frequency
is so high,
it's screwed up the recorder,
but whatever it is,
it isn't kidding,
and it's coming right at us.
It's headed this way.
Davey johnstone!
Duh.
What do you think?
Duh?
How many feet away, peter?
A hundred approximately.
- 75.
- Duh.
50.
See anything, stella?
No, I get nothing
on the surface.
It's not possible.
Keep looking.
25 feet,
and it's picking up speed.
Mm, ten feet, eight feet.
It's not a shark.
How would you know?
An electrician?
I'll bet it's not a shark.
You are such an electrician.
[Dolphins squeaking]
Dolphins win the super bowl!
Yay!
Twenty feet now.
Fifteen, he's...
It's turning.
Dammit, it's going away.
Turn.
It's diving.
It's going down.
Can you still follow him?
I didn't know he was
an electrician.
Now I'm losing him.
He's gone.
Thanks a lot, electrician.
[Audio rewinding]
Good morning, mr. European.
[Rumbling]
I know that sound.
It's an oil drum being dragged
across a garage floor.
The sound
of william conrad's heart.
What do you guys want?
I got beer, beer,
and, oh, hey, look.
There's a beer.
Sorry about that electrician
crack earlier.
My father's village
was attacked by electricians.
I never heard anything
quite like that.
Right.
They might be the sound
of a marine specimen
we don't know about.
And it sure scares the hell
out of all the other fish.
[Imitates burp]
Is that recording good enough
to identify the thing?
Maybe. But we don't have
the proper equipment.
- Mm.
- Right, bob?
Yeah, only that pig west
has it at w.O.I.
Pig.
The only thing he lacks
is a little humanity.
So I think our viking's
all wired up.
"Oh, my legs got bit off."
Be quiet, you baby.
[Groans softly]
Will he make it, doc?
We can only begin to hope.
Once he gets out of this coma.
I can only tell you we're
doing everything possible.
Sorry we had to put him
in this closet.
Ooh, charlie horse!
[Groans]
How does kissing him help?
Hang on. I got to stamp
a new price on it.
Intel steady at 35.
Nurse, four milligrams
of adrenaline. Quick.
[Sustained tone]
Come on.
His broadcast day is over.
Doctor, the adrenaline.
I'll squirt it
in the general area.
[Laughs]
Well, at least
he seems stabilized now.
Oh, I see now.
I had it set on "kill patient."
I'm sorry, sheriff.
You can't borrow
my smoked glasses.
He's dead.
His heart just gave out.
Well, I gave it out,
actually.
Yeah, it was fear.
Fear stopped his heart.
Well, you'd be scared too
if I was your doctor.
Behind the scenes
at mtv unplugged.
Ah.
Need a copy made, audience?
Scene's starting.
Pass it on.
We feel sure that whatever
is making that noise
hasn't been classified
as yet.
A fascinating thought.
I hope we can count
on your collaboration.
Your equipment is much more
up to date than ours.
♪♪ [Humming jaws theme]
There shouldn't
be any problem.
Of course not.
We're delighted
to assist anyone
who truly loves the sea
and its creatures
- the way we do.
- Aren't we?
Besides,
the possible discovery
of a hitherto unknown
marine species
would be of a historical
importance to all of us.
Cookies are ready.
You'll have to leave us
the recorded sounds, I'm afraid.
How much time
do you think you'll need?
However long it takes.
Hey, did you see that?
That guy
just bench-pressed me.
[Laughs]
♪♪ [Dramatic]
Beery guy's theme.
Okay, what is it now?
10, 10, 10, 10, 3-2-1, 10?
Hello, paleontological
institute?
"Pally"?
I'd like to speak
to mrs. Bates, please.
Janet bates.
Meanwhile,
in the world today...
[Phone beeping]
Joan baez fan.
Hello.
- Hello?
- Hello, sweetheart. I--
- oh, bob!
- Let me finish.
How nice
to hear your voice again.
Are you still
entertaining dolphins?
I'm calling for something
very important.
Catch the first plane
and come down.
Explain why.
What's up?
Well, as yet,
I'm not too sure.
Bring all your notes
on proto-sharks.
You're kidding.
I may be onto something
really incredible.
[Yawns]
I guess I'm tired.
Approximately 320 years ago,
new forms of fish developed.
Fish with teeth.
And among them was
the "dilictus,"
a deadly predator that measured
over 20 feet long.
The kronosaurus
descended from this species
and thrived
in the jurassic period.
Slide please.
[Imitates operatic singing]
...another awesome predator.
It appeared at the beginning
of the cetaceous period,
about 120 million years ago.
[All]
Boring.
We consider the true
ancestor of the shark
- as we know it today...
- [Imitates operatic singing]
...and it appeared at the end
of the cetaceous era,
60 million years ago.
Thanks, kotter's wife.
Now then. I studied
this cast very carefully,
and I fed the results of my
examination into the computer.
Hmm?
And she just got here
last night?
Duh, wha--wha?
Now, the comparative results
are not absolutely definitive,
but I think
I can safely say...
- Wah, wah, wah, wah, wah.
- ...That the creature found
in your part of the ocean
is a living fossil.
And that was the day
I met dick meeker.
Aw, that's nice.
You guys, we got a call
from this weird lady.
Real mean, but kinda stupid.
A lot of dishwater blonde hair.
Oh, mrs. Forrester.
- That's who it was.
- Yeah.
Anyway, she's gonna
be sending an electrician
up here to do some stuff.
- Thanks, gyps.
- Okay.
Hey, hey, an electrician.
So?
Oh, come on. Everybody
knows about electricians.
Um, mike, just because
the movie vaguely implies
that some electricians
may be lacking in something--
- are you mike?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna be installing
some grounded outlets
along the baseboard
back there.
Oh, okay. Great.
We need those.
So thanks.
I appreciate it.
Oh, mike.
Yeah. Uh, so anyway,
you should be able to run
your dehumidifier
off those, uh...
You know what?
I just wanna warn you.
You got a little spot
right there on your shirt.
Yeah. Okay.
- Oh, mike.
- It's embarrassing.
Oh, hey,
look at this, you guys.
You see, I know how
to use the phone,
because I'm an electrician.
[Mumbles, laughs]
[Laser fires]
Hey, mike.
Dolphin war bird uncloaking
off the port bow.
Oh!
Cambot,
give me rocket number nine.
What in blazes is going on?
I'll tell you,
after this movie came out,
we electricians started
having a lot of trouble.
Oh!
So we formed a mutual
defense pact with the dolphins.
Are they gonna kill us?
Unless your mouthy friend
here apologizes,
yeah, sure.
Mike.
Well, I'm sorry.
[Laser fires]
Apologize to us nicely.
Okay, okay.
I'm very sorry.
I apologize
to all electricians.
I realize now that electricians
provide a valuable service,
and possess a level
of technical knowledge
far beyond anything
I could ever grasp.
God bless electricians.
Great. I'll be getting back
to work then.
Okay. I am sorry.
Hey, idiot.
We got movie sign.
Which we could never have
without electricians.
Shut up.
[Alarm beeping]
- Doorknob.
- Jeez.
Feel kinda bad about it.
Hey.
What's a guy got to do
to get an oreo cookie
blizzard around here?
Ooh.
- Miller.
- Want an olive?
No, I only want you
to get lost.
We made a deal.
I gave you the key to the shop
only so you could take
the converter, and that's all.
Are you mad because
we roughed up your boyfriend?
Idiot.
There was a time
when you were a lot sweeter.
Yeah, and I prefer
not to think about it.
It's over. You got it?
All over.
You're gonna do exactly
what I tell you to do,
understand?
You are hurting me.
No,
I'm reminding you
that you'll be receiving
further instructions.
Towel boy's a real jerk.
[Imitating girl]
Boy, he was so mean to me.
I think
I'll go over there and...
[Mumbles]
[Imitating dramatic music]
I MUST CALL STEVE McGARRETT.
Hello?
I would like to speak
to sheriff gordon.
I'll wait.
No, you won't.
My mom might call.
[Chuckles]
Personal trainer
to paul reubens.
[Laughs]
Oh, you could have
put grandma's ashes
in a more
dignified container.
Fishing for deep sea clowns.
They're deploying
sea dreidels.
There.
I'm sick of these things.
They're just cluttering up
the deck and all.
Now does a rabbit
come out of the thing...
Does something. Ah, okay.
There. Good enough.
Mom will love this birthday gift
I made for her.
Ah, captain pantyhose.
What's that for?
Well, uh, basically,
we drop these
in various places
to cover the area
of surveillance.
Mm-hmm.
Each one has
a sensitive hydrophone
and this satellite
transmitter.
And they're connected
to a receiver in the computer.
Oh.
Then if our friend
comes in the area,
we'll pick him up.
Oh.
16th is a water hole
surrounded by water
on all sides.
I'm gonna put some
potpourri in the crow's nest.
YOU'RE SHOOTING IN 100 CCs?
Mm-hmm.
You think that's enough?
I hope so.
The dose would put
a whale to sleep.
Hmm.
Oh, that allen funt
turns up everywhere.
They're gonna see a dolphin
robbing a 7-eleven.
- Oh, good.
- You made muffins.
It's directional.
But to be sure
we pick 'em up,
I think it's best
if we have the camera
mounted at the bow.
Then that's where
we'll have it.
The beer's over there
in that box.
Wouldn't it be great
if you were devil fishing
and they had beer?
Really watery
american beer.
Up the shark's ass.
You know, after this beer,
we should have a beer sometime.
Mm.
I thought only dolphins
emitted sound.
Well, dolphins
have a language,
but all fish emit sounds,
and rather complex ones.
[Device beeps]
Ooh, right.
Our mission and stuff.
Hey, we got visitors.
Bearing down at 235 degrees.
That's six degrees
off the port beer. I mean bow.
[Laughs]
Hey, we're winning
the whitbread cup.
What is it?
It's the challenger.
West is spying on us.
Think he could be after
our friend too?
Oh, I wouldn't
put it past him.
He's very ambitious.
He'd sit
on his mother's head
if he had something
to gain by it.
Hot image, bob.
Peter, I'm not getting
a signal from buoy #4 anymore.
[Peter]
Okay, hang on.
Looks like
a new thomas dolby song.
[Growling]
Hm, little rich
on the bass there.
Why couldn't I have been
wendell corey?
Let's see now.
Here's the church.
Here's the steeple.
Oh, damn,
I've got to practice.
I wonder if I can order
cocktails online.
Let's just see
what the calista flockhart
web site
has to say about the shark.
[Electronic voice]
Sea killer.
Information classified.
Access denied.
Thanks a lot, stephen hawking.
♪ Karma karma karma
karma karma chameleon ♪
♪♪ [soft rock]
Enjoy the soft-core porn
soundtrack.
Ben! Ben!
Man, if he stops short,
she'll have quite a trajectory.
Part of her job description
is prow.
Let's head over
to pogo's place.
Wow, they caught
a giant eyeball.
Looks like
it's been sabotaged.
But we haven't seen any boats
for the past hour.
Hm, better take off your suit
and flag down some help.
Yeah, except the challenger.
We still have four at least.
It doesn't work that way.
In order to cover the field,
we've got to have all five
functioning.
Let's get back to the boat.
They're having mambo lessons
on the lido deck.
Didn't she star in the nightmare
before christmas?
What's the matter?
Felt like something's caught
in the prop.
That's a prop?
I thought it was a real motor.
[Peter]
Yeah, that's all we need.
Ah, the giant ocean shar pei.
Janet.
I got the amiga working.
This may be it.
You're getting
the same picture?
I like you.
Look at that guy there,
grabbing at his own evinrude.
Oh, wait.
See the human lady.
You haven't finished?
You didn't even try
to give me a hand.
You've been loafing.
That's 'cause it's so hot.
Yeah. Not here.
Come on in.
Yuck, he's trying to be sexy.
You know,
she displaces no water at all.
Huh, this scene
omitted for content.
The devil fish insisted
that it be shot through a filter
to make him look younger.
I really think it's him.
It's heading for us.
He's made out of poached salmon.
Where are peter and stella?
They're off being scrawny.
I can't see
their boat from here.
It's strange, though,
that they--
[gasps]
The devil fish is on the roof.
That's him.
Yes.
Is he bringing them a piano?
What's happening?
It changed direction.
No, it's leaving.
Come back.
I'm a recovering alcoholic.
I can't eat that guy.
Come on, baby.
Come back, baby.
Blake edwards, point 10.
Can anyone tell me
if I have a butt yet?
No, huh?
Minor boat inconveniences
splayed across the screen.
Look, he's just hanging his
evinrude right out there
in the--
[mumbling]
He's gone.
Yeah. He must be around here.
He couldn't have gone far.
- Why not?
- Because I have his car keys.
I don't know.
I just sense that these are
his native waters.
What did I tell you?
He's coming back to me.
NOW IT'S 10 AS REWRITTEN
BY TERRENCE McNALLY.
Look, he's built
like a g.i. joe.
He even has shoulder sockets
so you can pose him.
[Slow motion voice]
I love you.
Uh, what?
You want to...
Oh, okay, just don't expect me
to help.
So there's a huge, giant couple
making out behind them?
They're cloning.
Hey, the other us is getting
ahead of us.
Wakka-wakka-wakka-wacka.
Ow. Ow. You just laid me
on a puffer fish.
- As seen on tv.
- ♪♪ [suspenseful]
They simply play
the jaws theme backwards.
The telecamera.
Look at the monitor.
It's the blue show,
starring blue.
- Well?
- I don't see anything.
It's getting near.
It's almost off the bow.
15 degrees to port.
Hi, blue here.
My first guest is teal.
Bob, there's something
on the screen.
It's flying toasters.
- See it?
- Yes.
It might be him,
but the picture
isn't very clear.
Hang on.
I'll get a little closer.
Look. Look.
Sandra bullock
and charles haid look on.
My god.
Bob, it's coming right at us.
Pure coincidence,
I assure you.
[Bob]
Look at that.
I can't believe it.
Look at those tentacles.
A shark with tentacles.
Plus the great taste
of chicken.
[Gasps]
Coffee's done.
It's right underneath us.
I know!
Was this guy dubbed
by j. Peterman?
Where are you going?
What are you going to do?
I know!
Try and put him to sleep.
I'm going to read him
something from joan didion.
It's like shooting fish...
Not in a barrel.
Slowly I acted, step by step.
Hey, you got a beer for me?
Stella!
Bob, look out!
I know!
[Screams]
Oh, bob!
Behind you!
Look out!
[Monster roars]
It's so big
it's a eleven-tacle.
That's your second one.
Every time I meet a guy,
he's married, gay,
or getting killed
by a giant octopus.
Mm, human sushi.
I love this stuff.
Say good-bye to beer for me.
Are those easy spirit pumps?
Oh, she never got to wear
a hip bone revealing
bathing suit.
This is why I got rid of my
monstrously large octopus.
Yeah. Think that was wise.
Man, she's strong.
She works out at a gym
where she
hangs 5,000-pound fish
off her torso.
Ow! Please, no,
that's my dominant tentacle.
No, not that one.
I use it to open lobster cages.
Heh-heh,
he's never faced
a mediocre woman
with a small hand ax before.
- Bob?
- Ray?
You know that door's
not even red,
and I want to paint it black.
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
It's okay.
I feel european
upon seeing that.
You better take off your suit
and wipe that up.
Once again there's noodles
in bob's throw up.
I know of no other course
but to start making out again.
Bob?
- [Sobbing]
- I hate the way you say "bob."
It's all right.
Janet, it's all right.
It's us.
I thought you were the octopus
in disguise.
Bob's boat was attacked here.
Whole dang thing just sits
in that area.
- Must like it.
- The perv.
How are they doing, cortez?
They haven't spotted it yet.
Yeah, that's what
I was afraid of.
They want to come in.
Tell them to sit tight
until further notice.
Yo.
Fantastic.
Your hair--
it smells fantastic.
Hogan really hit
the jackpot this time.
Shame he's dead.
My files show it's
not a shame, sir.
The computer analysis says
that it's 40 feet long.
Lucky bastard.
Its jaws can open up
six feet wide.
And its underwater speed is
more than 30 knots.
Are those don knotts?
That's a real torpedo.
So that's all the info, right?
That's all?
Don't you understand
that this data alone
is enough for us to claim
a major scientific discovery.
All I want to know
is how do you catch it?
From deep-mouth kissing.
I might have an idea.
Doesn't all animal life
respond to the calls
of its own kind?
You seem to forget we're dealing
with one of a kind.
It's amazing it survived
at all.
Would my good looks help
in any way?
I've recorded its voice
and can reproduce it
with only slight modulations.
Close enough to make it think
that the sounds
of one of its own species.
That'll come made
with our boat.
I don't think it'll work.
I'd like to try it.
Man, what an electrician lover.
Yeah, a million years
of solitude is a long time.
I'll be he's just dying
to bull with someone.
You know what I think?
You're being ridiculous.
David. Take a look.
Here are the first findings
on the lab analysis
we ran
on the animal's tentacle.
Oh, hey,
it's a hoochie-coochie fist.
It has a primordial biological
structure,
extremely resistant.
Average age of cells...
[Electronic voice]
Eight months.
Oh, my god, is that possible?
Eight months?
The cells of this creature
have a life of...
Only eight months?
I'm gonna kick your ass.
I don't believe it.
You mean that that monster
is nothing but a pup?
[Chattering]
Should we have tied
this stuff down?
I mean, it is explosive.
[Groans]
Orson welles toilet float.
[Man on phone]
We want a nice clean job.
They have to be stopped
at all costs.
- Okay.
- Got it?
Stopped at all costs.
Use your face if necessary.
Hey, sheriff, they killed
that girl, sandra hayes.
She worked for peter.
You know where
they murdered her?
Harrison bay.
I'm winded.
I ran all the way from gnc.
I had considered quitting.
I was bored.
Now there are people
getting killed like flies,
right in front of my nose.
Sheriff,
I think there's a connection
between these deaths
and the monster's appearance.
Go stuff your face
with steroids.
You've got a good future,
fernando.
Don't foul it up.
- Where you going?
- Harrison bay.
Won't take us long
to attach it,
but when you see
the red light come on,
turn it off.
You ready, peter?
Okay.
We're going to do
underwater cheerleading.
Thanks. Right on top of me.
You know, I hope they stay
under water a long time
and don't do anything
but swim around,
and we get to see
every second of it.
Hm. Yeah.
Let's tip it,
just to scare her.
Look, she's power pouting.
Bob filled the pool with zima.
Two years of braces,
and this is the result.
My bikini is frightened.
Oh, I shouldn't have eaten
european food.
Boat's made out of concrete.
God.
Wonder if it's powered
by his face.
♪ Yeah, divin' now, oh yeah ♪
♪ chasin' the devil fish,
oh yeah ♪
♪ scared lady now, oh yeah. ♪
[Boat engine chugging]
Permission for ugly face
to board.
I'm here for the orangutan
look-alike contest.
An inflated
kris kristofferson.
Look at all those bubbles.
They are really farting.
Oh, man.
[Trills lips]
And now the news.
And now the news again.
And now some more news.
And that's the news.
Man, what an aggressive
steak knife salesman.
♪♪ [Humming]
Why is she wearing a giant
tube of easy cheese?
I don't...
Glasses from the brett somers
collection.
If I can just hold him off
till the knife rusts.
I could throw a perch at him.
Damn, it's rust proof.
However,
if we fight much longer,
the knife will become
encrusted with barnacles
and be rendered ineffective.
Ew, right in the fabric
softener packet.
Should I call 911?
I'm devil fish, for polident.
He's got a coast guard guy
stuck in his molars.
Underwater fights
are like the drum solos
of movies.
Hey, you.
Say I look like micky dolenz.
Turn around.
Turn, I said.
Wanna sign your birthday card
before I give it to you.
I had to cut the power to your
mask while I work on it.
[Gasps]
Who am I?
Please, don't let me die
before I know who I am.
At least its poor editing
covers how badly it was shot.
Yeah, it's a movie
that constantly reassures you,
you don't need to concern
yourself with this.
Oh, I've gotta get out
of this wet suit
and get into my wet jeans
and wet sweatshirt.
An almodovar film.
Hey, scooter, buddy!
Whoo!
Oh, boy.
My face-- it's not waterproof.
The devil fish
is always there.
Does he have a police scanner
or something?
Peter!
Action back fat.
♪♪ [Humming]
[Mock gasping]
Devil fish got out
of a live well.
[Man screaming]
I've just gotta hug you, kid.
It's so good to see you.
What a shame to be killed
by calamari.
Okay, that's quite enough male
hiney shots for me.
Still a better edited movie
than batman & robin.
Yep.
The ocean's on spin cycle.
Did the director think
this guy was hot?
That's a nice butt, mike.
Maybe you're right.
[Crashing sound]
Someone just bowl?
Ed wood's octopus scene
was a lot more convincing
than this.
Could you go head first?
I don't have that wide
a jaw span.
I have a cramp.
I ate a full meal
55 minutes ago.
You can do it.
Janet.
Oh, sorry, I forgot.
I'm nasty.
Miss jackson!
- Oh.
- Stella.
Oh, no, she's--
ooh, she's fat. Ew.
Careful, she might not be dead
and start flopping around.
♪♪ [Soft rock]
Is this really
an appropriate place
for the soft-core porn music?
Ivan lendl and richard marx.
- What's going on?
- ♪ what's going on? ♪
♪ I say, yay, yay, yay, yay ♪
Whoever it is clearly doesn't
want us to get that creature.
What? What's that, cambot?
What? Look at ourselves
on the monitor, boy?
Okay. Why, we all look
vaguely italian.
Vaguely.
Better one?
Or... better two?
Yeah, vaguely italian, mike,
but it's not good enough.
See, our guests
were enjoying devil fish,
but then having you guys
pop in periodically
and do whatever it is
you do up there,
well, it kind of confused them.
So I'm trying this special
image and sound filter
on the projector
to make you guys look
all italiany,
like the actors
in the movie.
It'll ease the transition
for them
and make you less noticeable,
which is good.
And you won't feel a thing.
Okay, go a level up.
Okay.
[Italian accent]
Pearl, what do you do this for?
I don't know, mike.
I kind of like-a the look.
I can't-a wait to go
to the beach-a
and wear a tiny g-string
and a gold-a chain-a.
You're-a turning us
into broad stereotypes-a.
I know, I know.
I'm sorry, but these
adjustments are very delicate.
Here, let me try it.
No, get your hand--
no, look out.
Too much.
No, look out. Oh, no!
Hey, gondola ride for-a you
and the lady, signore monkey.
Why you break-a
your mama's heart?
Mangia, mangia.
Hey, pearl, turn it off.
You make us such broad
caricatures.
♪ Oh, sole mio ♪
Oh, we got a commercial sign.
Anthony! Anthony!
Phew, I did not like that.
Let's see if I can get
aldo nova in better here.
Hey, amoeba porn.
That's impossible.
That was great.
Was it good for me, too?
This changes everything.
Yeah, all right.
Cortez, there's an urgent
phone call for the sheriff.
Dr. West. Something important
about the monster.
Get him on the car phone.
My skin is really dry.
[Phone buzzes]
Yeah, gordon speaking.
Jeff, I've just discovered
something terrifying.
Carol channing nude.
Our monster
can reproduce itself.
What?
The monster
can reproduce itself?
You've got to be kidding.
Monster can reproduce itself.
I've never been more serious
in my life, sheriff.
♪♪ [Humming jaws theme]
Every cell of that creature
is capable of reproducing
similar creatures.
I have here before me
cells we've taken
from the tentacle.
They're reproducing
at an incredible rate.
It's a fantastic spectacle.
Doctor, are you telling me
if the monster's wounded,
the shreds of flesh can
reproduce?
- No.
- Exactly.
So the coast guard
just rolled over
for the italian film industry?
It swallows the bait
and the charge goes off,
we could find ourselves...
- What? I can hear you?
- Huh?
...radio'd in.
It'll take hours to collect
those buoys.
We don't have enough time.
How are we going to do it?
Take me down to the buoy area.
I won a free-fire gold medal
at the police academy
in sarasota.
I'm a little bit rusty,
but here goes.
Yeah, pretty much peaked
in sarasota.
Ryan, stabilize 20 yards
above that buoy.
Okay.
So the coast guard's
off filming this,
and drug runners
are cruising right through.
There are seven more.
I've got to find them.
Take me around.
I love creating buddy lists.
Sea killer information
classified.
Access denied.
Playing coy, eh?
I like that.
- This is west.
- Access denied.
- Okay, then this is east.
- Who has access?
Not authorized to respond.
All right, let's try
another approach.
I'll slip
into a negligee and...
Are you able to accept info
useful to the sea killer
project?
[Imitating elmer fudd]
Sea kiwwer?
Heh-heh-heh-heh-heh.
We've gotta take out
these hoppity hops.
Very good, sir.
You won a plush toy.
There's one missing, sheriff.
Hey, look.
What's that shadow under us?
It's louie anderson.
That's him.
♪ C'est moi, c'est moi ♪
There he is.
He's heading for the buoy.
Start going in.
You know,
they appeared in this.
I bet the coast guard
would appear in my brother's
wedding video.
Oh, yeah.
[Gun fires]
Mr. Gold medal, come on.
Not my balloon!
Project sea killer
classification-- top secret.
Animal has been programmed
to control designated area.
[Imitating computer]
...test suspended august '84.
Cause-- auto prototyp--
tip, tip, type...
[Stammering]
Man, just wanted
to play freecell.
Project originator--
dr. Davis.
- Davis, davis, davis...
- Davis, davis, davis?
Unoriginal parents.
Ow.
I will seek my revenge,
but first I'm going to snag me
a charleston chew.
Yeah, I'm going to go
to the stacks
and leaf through
old life magazines.
- Hold it.
- You have overdue books.
I see you've finally discovered
the truth, dr. West.
Let's say my suspicions
are now confirmed.
However, I'd like to know
why you've persisted
in spite of my opposition.
Because our future
is in the sea.
Anyone who has the chance
to tap the tremendous reserves
of the sea
will have the future, doctor.
- In his hands.
- Exactly.
Thanks for helping me
out there.
Why create such a monster?
What better way
to protect and exploitable area
than a marine monster
almost indestructible
and whose genetic
characteristics
are as fearsome
as the white shark's?
- ♪♪ [humming jaws theme]
A gigantic octopus
with the intelligence
of a dolphin
and as monstrous
as a prehistoric creature.
You're mad.
No, you're the one who's mad.
Sonja, please.
Because you don't understand
our magnificent creation
and what it will mean
to the company.
- The w.O.I...
- Woi.
...has only one objective--
profits.
Don't forget that.
Look, from a woman who has
the sensitivity of a slut
to the point of giving
her lover
the identical watch
she gave her husband
for an anniversary present,
I will not accept less than...
I'm sorry.
It's a very nice watch.
That monster
has already caused the death
of a number of innocent people,
and I doubt it will ever
become a means
of profit to anybody.
It won't succeed.
It'll be easier
than you think,
and you won't be able
to stop us.
So neh.
In 12 hours
that creature's
cellular structure
will begin to disintegrate,
and the seas will be populated
by identical creatures
that will continue
to reproduce themselves
indefinitely
until the oceans
the world over
will be totally dominated
by them.
You're envious.
The truth is you've become
too old, west,
too old for science,
too old for your wife.
Don't move, davis.
Pre-dried,
immediately spread blood.
- Davis!
- But he did say, "don't move."
You'll never stop him.
You'll never be able...
Oh, man,
even in death he won't shut up.
You won't ever be able
to destroy my creature.
Please, francisco franco
died quicker.
Can this marriage be saved?
It's not my fault!
- [Sheriff] Cortez.
- [Cortez] Yeah.
It was his idea.
- No!
- Okay, lady.
It's not my fault!
It ain't mine either,
so let's get out of here.
How long had you been
standing there, sheriff?
I got her just in time
to hear who the maniac was
behind all this.
It's richard jewell.
We have one possibility,
sheriff.
Oh, really?
What's that?
- Fire.
- ♪♪ [hums arthur brown's
"fire"]
Those cells can be destroyed
by fire.
How are we going
to burn a monster
hiding at the bottom
of the sea?
Lure it to the surface.
To the surface?
Of course.
Peter can do it with
a tape recorder.
We tried it and it works.
Okay, it's worth a try.
Remember,
there's very little time,
perhaps less than eight hours.
So let's get our fastest boat
on the project.
Isn't anybody here
going to bribe me?
[Foreign accent]
Come on.
I need to contact europe.
Mike, how come you don't have
huge rubber pants?
Who says I don't?
- Ow.
- Yow.
Watch it!
♪ Get your flamethrowers out,
grab a stick of juicyfruit ♪
Attention.
Free devil fish food.
Farrah fawcett minor.
Okay, see anything yet, stella?
What's on the screen?
Negative.
- What do you mean, negative?
- All right, keep calling him.
The ox-fish incident.
Sheriff gordon here.
You read me?
- Negative.
- What is it, sheriff?
We're getting ready to give
a nice little reception.
Get it to surface
here in the canal
and we'll snare it.
- Yeah.
- Sure, whatever.
Morning.
How's it going?
The men have taken up
their position.
Make sure everything
is checked out.
I don't want any goof-ups
when the time comes.
Goofus?
Free coupons
to devil fish world.
Ooh, gingivitis.
That's him.
Okay.
No, wait.
That's his brother.
They look a lot alike.
We're coming in, sheriff.
Finally. You're around
a mile and a half from here.
Okay, we'll stop,
and I'll board the tender.
Tell the chopper pilot to be
on the ready, sheriff.
We're leading him in.
I'll be on the chopper myself,
peter.
Over and out.
If I don't come back,
adopt a single currency,
eat snails, and don't shave
your arm pits.
Ready to turn off
your tape call.
Okay.
Now.
I'm just going to turn
everything off.
That's easier.
Hey, grits gresham.
Anyway.
The ship's having shiplets.
Okay, peter, it's behind you.
You think the coast guard
would be in my niece's
high-school play?
- Sure.
- In a minute.
Nice going, peter.
Right on course.
Ahead of you,
you'll see the inlet.
I'm peter, and ahead of me
I see the inlet.
As seen on tv.
Where is that?
Be careful, peter.
It's getting too close.
Go faster.
No, I won't be careful,
and I'll go slower.
Follow me for free devil fish
marshmallow treats.
It's don evinrude
and sonny crockett.
Oh, I did it again, didn't I?
- Yeah.
- It's just not firing.
I'm coming in.
Cortez's men,
be on the ready.
...crew on stand-bye.
Let go of
the light surface fires.
Go on in.
Deploy the country time
pink lemonade.
Bet they hired every
nature-hating psycho
in dade county.
What a fun, festive way
to have a fish boil.
Peter, the thing's
on top of you.
Not unlike you and I earlier.
That's his answer
to everything.
As seen on tv.
I'm in the mood
for a little italian.
- Peter.
- I have a tummy ache.
Peter, where're lowering
a harness.
It's real sexy.
We want you to try it on.
Hoist! Hoist!
Cheek ski. Whoo!
Well, this is florida.
Maybe some fresh cubans
will do.
Whoa, did I see a...?
Uh, yep, yep, yep,
we have bike rack.
Whoo-hoo!
It's harpo.
Yep, I should empty
these pants soon.
So we've only got
a few hours left.
And I wanted to feel
your embrace before we die.
Squad number one,
do you read me?
Squad number one, sheriff.
Ain't seen nothing yet.
B-b-b-baby, we ain't seen
nothing yet. Over.
Report in, squad number two.
Squad number two,
come in, please.
Hm?
Squad number two.
♪♪ [Hums "dueling banjos"]
A few crackers
for an appetizer.
Chomp.
Squad number two.
We done been hit.
Over.
Squad number two,
come in please.
They'll be number two
soon enough.
Come on.
Let's go.
Squad number two
doesn't answer.
Get on. Quick.
Barry switzer
crosses the delaware.
This is how I like to fish,
mate.
A flash light
and a flame thrower.
You know, I don't need
neil young around anyhow.
Here, boy.
My heart will go on.
♪ Southern man,
gonna eat your head ♪
Lot of guys named bo
were killed that day.
So I guess we find out
what the south
is gonna do again--
get eaten by a huge fish.
Give me your hand.
No, just the hand.
It's okay.
The gas!
Pour out the gas!
All squads,
empty out containers.
Well, this should take care
of every living thing
in the everglades.
Yeah.
Flame throwers, ignite.
Here, try my cigar lighter.
Okay, now throw in
the diced onions and celery
and chopped
porcini mushrooms.
Does the coast guard
have a lot of use
for flame throwers?
And the cry of "opa" rings out.
All right, men.
See if he's done.
Try flaking him with a fork.
The sheriff's official report
simply read, "ick."
[Sniffs]
Mm.
Someone threw a match
on the cuyahoga river.
♪♪ [Hums "oh susannah"]
- Oh.
- No.
Aah! It's starting over.
No!
What is that?
There's nothing there.
You should start seeing
motorcycles, mike.
- Very nice, you guys.
- Thank you.
I'm finally getting
my vacation.
Where are we going?
To the mountains.
[Mock laughs]
We are from europe.
[All mock laughing]
[Laughter continuing]
[Continuing]
Okay. Oh, that's--
that's--
that's good, you guys.
Well, anyway, mike.
I think w.O.I.
Was on the right track,
attempting to raise profits
by combining a shark
and an octopus.
I just think it may have been
the wrong combination.
I mean, what about combining
a poodle and a fly?
No, no, no, not quite yet.
What about a snail
and a parrot?
No, close but not there.
What about you, servo?
What would you combine?
Who, me? I think I'll combine
a lick and a me and
ship it right over to you.
- Now, come on now.
- What the heck does he care
anyway?
I just think that
was completely uncalled for.
- Now down to you.
- Ridiculous.
I'm just trying to figure out
the movie.
Hey, nelson lose-dela,
we almost got
these bass-ackwards
chicken-fried idiots
into thinking
this is a cruise ship.
Now we just have to get
through the captain's dinner.
What could possibly go wrong?
[Clears throat]
As captain of this castle--
ow. And by castle,
I mean ship,
I'd like to welcome you
to my table.
Waiter, if you'd serve the crap,
please.
Your scallops in herbed butter,
crushed and toasted,
and served with tiny blue
marshmallows, madam.
Uh, captain, when will we
be allowed up on deck?
- Captain?
- Ow, quit hitting me.
- Well, answer the nice...
[Growling]
The tranquilizer gun!
[Gun pops]
Will there be anything else?
- Uh, no, we're good.
- Good.
[Gun pops]
[Gasps]
- Bob, it's right underneath us.
- I know!